<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>docker/vms on lunarwhite</title><link>https://lunarwhite.github.io/tags/docker/vms/</link><description>Recent content in docker/vms on lunarwhite</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© lunarwhite</copyright><atom:link href="https://lunarwhite.github.io/tags/docker/vms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[MIT-missing] 07 Potpourri, Q&amp;A</title><link>https://lunarwhite.github.io/posts/notes/mitmissing7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 19:41:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lunarwhite.github.io/posts/notes/mitmissing7/</guid><description>Potpourri - missing-semester
Q&amp;amp;A - missing-semester
1 Daemons Most computers have a series of processes that are always running in the background rather than waiting for a user to launch them and interact with them. These processes are called daemons and the programs that run as daemons often end with a d to indicate so. For example sshd, the SSH daemon, is the program responsible for listening to incoming SSH requests and checking that the remote user has the necessary credentials to log in.</description></item><item><title>Install linux in vmware virtual machine</title><link>https://lunarwhite.github.io/posts/devtools/vm-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 16:59:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lunarwhite.github.io/posts/devtools/vm-linux/</guid><description>本文简单介绍了Linux基本的开发环境配置，基于VMware虚拟机，搭配Ubuntu LTS，借助ssh工具和host机联络，比较舒适
1 安装部署 创建 2G/16G/2 关闭3D/USB3.1/虚拟化/移除打印机 xx72/LA/vmlnx/xx 安装VMTool # extract here # open in terminal # root sudo su # install ./vmware-install.pl 设置 2 卸载预装 # 卸载 dpkg -l | grep gnome sudo apt-get remove --purge -y gnome-bluetooth sudo apt-get remove --purge -y gnome-calculator sudo apt-get remove --purge -y gnome-characters sudo apt-get remove --purge -y gnome-disk-utility sudo apt-get remove --purge -y gnome-font-viewer sudo apt-get remove --purge -y gnome-logs sudo apt-get remove --purge -y gnome-online-accounts sudo apt-get remove --purge -y gnome-power-manager sudo apt-get remove --purge -y gnome-screenshot sudo apt-get remove --purge -y gnome-system-monitor sudo apt-get remove --purge -y gnome-user-docs dpkg -l | grep firefox sudo apt-get remove --purge -y firefox sudo apt-get remove --purge -y firefox-locale-en 3 清理空间 # 删除系统不再使用的孤立软件 sudo apt-get autoremove --purge # 清理旧版本的软件缓存 sudo apt-get autoclean # 清理所有软件缓存 sudo apt-get clean # 清理缩略图缓存 rm -rf ~/.</description></item></channel></rss>